Most of us know what it's like to get presents from friends.
我们大多数人都知道从朋友那里收到礼物是什么感觉。
Whether it's for a birthday or other celebration, it's hard to beat the excitement of opening a carefully wrapped box to find something that's both unexpected and suits you perfectly.
无论是生日还是其他庆祝活动，打开一个精心包裹的盒子，发现既出乎意料又完美适合你的东西，这种兴奋感无与伦比。
Now, imagine if you could get the same feeling when you go shopping for yourself.
现在，想象一下如果你自己购物时也能获得同样的感觉。
That's the feeling that mystery boxes hope to replicate.
这就是盲盒希望复制的感觉。
Mystery boxes are not a new idea – they were a feature of department stores in Japan in the early 20th Century.
盲盒并不是一个新想法——它们是20世纪初日本百货商店的一个特色。
They contain a range of different products, which are sold at a lower price than their combined value.
它们包含一系列不同的产品，售价低于它们的总价值。
The key thing is that customers don't know what's in the box before they buy.
关键点是顾客在购买前不知道盒子里有什么。
All kinds of mystery boxes are available: fashion boxes, food boxes, beauty boxes, even loot boxes, which are virtual items for video games.
各种各样的神秘盒子都有：时尚盒、食品盒、美妆盒，甚至是战利品盒，即用于电子游戏的虚拟物品。
The pleasant surprise is not the only attraction of mystery boxes.
惊喜并不是盲盒的唯一吸引力。
They also allow people to try things that they otherwise wouldn't.
它们还让人们尝试他们原本不会尝试的东西。
Seasonal vegetable subscription boxes might lead people to learn to cook new meals.
季节性蔬菜订阅盒可能会引导人们学习烹饪新的菜肴。
They can also potentially offer great savings – as the recommended retail price of the contents is often far higher than the purchase price.
它们还可能会省钱——因为里面物品的建议零售价通常远高于购买价格。
For retailers and suppliers the benefits are clear – it allows them to sell unwanted stock for a profit.
对于零售商和供应商来说，好处是显而易见的——这使他们能够出售不需要的库存来获利。
British fashion mystery box entrepreneur Mario Maher highlights how mystery boxes can help reduce the amount of waste in the fashion industry.
英国时尚盲盒企业家马里奥·马希尔强调了盲盒如何帮助减少时尚行业的浪费量。
People might discover product ranges that would otherwise be thrown away.
人们可能会发现一些产品系列，不然的话它们将会被扔掉。
There is an obvious downside to mystery boxes – when you buy them, you don't know what you'll get!
盲盒有一个明显的缺点——当你购买它们时，你不知道会得到什么！
It may be that the goods inside are not to your taste, but there is also the potential for fraudsters to exploit the unpredictability of mystery boxes to send items that have a much lower value than the price of the box.
里面的商品可能不合你的口味，但骗子也有可能利用盲盒的不可预测性，安排价值远低于盒子价格的物品。
So, are mystery boxes a fun way of reducing waste and making shopping more exciting, or more an opportunity for disappointment, or worse – deception?
那么，盲盒是一种减少浪费、让购物更刺激的有趣方式，还是更可能带来失望，或者更糟——欺骗的机会呢？